Antitrust Tim Robbins Crime 2001
720p [H246-mp4] Subtitles English.
This business
is a living organism.
Multiplying constantly
surrounded by predators.
There's no rule for idle
time or second guessing,
New discoveries are made hourly.
New ideas are ready to be
devoured and redefined.
This business is binary.
You're a one or a zero.
Alive or dead.
There is no second place.
It's been suggested by
the media and congress
that you're violating antitrust
laws, and threatening competition.
Mr. Winston, can you
reasonably deny
that you have a
monopoly in this area?
Well, the only monopoly
we have at N.U.R.V, congressman,
is monopoly on excellence.
This is still a free market.
But a free market
encourages competition.
You prevent it.
Congressman, I don't need to remind
you that the essence of competition
has always been quite simple.
Any kid working in a garage
anywhere in the world,
with a good idea, can
put us out of business.
You can try a version qualification
scheme if you have the best driver.
Wait a second.. go back up.
Move, move.
Teddy, I think I found
our bottleneck.
- You did it!
- Yee-Haw!
God! That feels good.
It's gorgeous!
We're geeks.
Three months from today,
N.U.R.V will launch SYNAPSE,
transforming the way
humans communicate,
With Synapse,
the entire world will be able
to send or receive any message
be it audio, video or
text on any medium.
SYNAPSE will fully unite
the global village.
You've set yourself real
ticking clock here, Gary.
All of your competitors are desperate to get to
the marketplace with this technology before you.
It has even been suggested
that you won't hit this
very ambitious launch date.
We're going to hit that
date. You can bet on it.
How can you be sure?
We'll do whatever it
takes... to get there.
Pace yourself, Brian.
Over here...
Milo, what do you think of this?
I know I promised my mom we're
gonna make this garage famous,
but I really don't think we're
gonna be here that long.
'Cause I've got us 3 appointments
with the venture capitalists.
Oh, that is fantastic
I can stop taking calls from those
corporate recruitment losers.
I'll do the talking, Brian.
Here's your shirt, Milo.
Guys, what are these?
Don't you know? The worse you look,
the smarter they think you are.
They are going to think
you're a genius, Brian.
I just said "Milo" and "Teddy",
and the wallets flew open!
They were dying to
give me their money.
You guys are the greatest duo,
since Hewlett and Packard.
Lennon and McCartney.
Ben and Jerry!
I'm Lennon, okay Teddy?
Does that make me Yoko?
Alice, you've got to make him
do this start up with Teddy.
Gary, if he wants to go take a few
interviews... check out his options,
as his friend, I think you
should support him in that.
Want to know the best way
to manipulate somebody?
Yeah.
Don't try.
"As graduating students for the Stanford
University Computer Science department,
"you have a magnificent
foundation... in theory.
"What you need is a creative,
innovative..." So pretentious!
- The guy's a fascist monopolist.
- Exactly.
The guy knows how to get
people's attention. He does.
Shut up... shut up!
I'm trying to listen.
"Will field your questions."
"Thanks for taking the
time to check us out."
"I'll look forward to seeing some of you up
here at the NURV campus in the near future."
- Questions, cool!
- I've got a question for him.
"If you guys have
questions, fire away."
Why not make SYNAPSE
open source?
Don't you have
enough money? Heh.
Here is an interesting question:
"What kind of beverages do
you offer your programmers?"
- Oh, come on!
- What did you expect?
- He's avoiding the issue, man.
- You can't ask him that.
He should run for
president, or something.
I'm just gonna of throw these at you.
You know, like they do at the zoo.
Hello.
It's for you.
- Hello.
- Milo? This is Gary Winston.
I've heard great things
about your work, I'm...
hoping you and your friend
Teddy can come up here.
Hey, Larry, you still
got my Union Jack CD?
No, I gave it back.
Ok, I don't know who this is
but your timing really blows
'cause I just saw
him in a live chat.
Right, well, a pair of airline
tickets are on there way to you,
I'd love to show you some of
the things we're doing here.
Who was it?
Gary Winston.
Ha, that would be funny.
I just spoke to Gary Winston?
I can't believe you're not
going to take that ticket!
Give it to me!
You don't want to
work there, Brian.
They squeeze everybody out of business.
They get bigger and fatter...
That's why I want to work there.
You sure he didn't
ask for my number?
Milo, we can't go up there.
They don't even know the
meaning of open source.
You know this, we've
talked about this.
They just want to
own everything!
- They clone stuff, reverse engineer it...
- I know.
Everybody is stuck with their
inferior proprietary version.
They're being investigated by the
justice department for Christ's sake.
Tell him, Larry.
I think that he should go up there
and check it out if he is curious.
You do?
Sure, I mean... it's your life.
I need another beer.
So, you couldn't convince
your friend Teddy to come?
No, he is pretty tight
with his folks.
Yeah? We can move them up
here same goes for yours.
My parents are dead.
I'm sorry man.
So how far is the campus?
We're not going to campus.
All I can say is
it's unfortunate.
We offered a lot of money. A
substantial amount of money, Gary.
No sale.
Can we buy into their stock? Or is
that a Justice Department problem too?
There is no stock, Randy. I
mean there's no company!
Gary Winston's office.
Can you hold, please?
Thanks for holding.
Yes, he is in a conference right
now. Can I take a message?
The cold, hard facts are
that anything is possible.
Anything, anything. You're
just not thinking creatively.
I have every confidence
that you can do that, Phil.
- It's a difficult one but we're going to prevail.
- All right, all right.
Gary Winston's office.
Let me check that for you.
I'm sorry, I don't
see anything new.
Milo?
Hi.
It's not everyday we have
genius in the house.
- Want a soda pop or something?
- No, thanks.
Come on in.
Digital canvas.
The house knows the paintings I
like, knows my favourite music.
Same for anybody else
that's in the system.
There's a little sensor that
detects who's in the room.
Doesn't Bill Gates have
something like that?
Bill who? Heh.
No, no. His is primitive.
So I understand you're
thinking of doing a start up.
Yeah.
My friends and I have been planning on doing
a media delivery system for a long time.
It would be open source, we'd...
offer it free for everybody,
just charge for tech support.
Wow, free.
This is a cut-throat
business we're in, Milo.
It's just a matter of time before
someone "borrows" your technology,
improves it and makes a
billion dollars on it.
What would you do with a
billion dollars, Milo?
I don't know.
I'll tell you what you could do.
You could take that money and
put it back into technology,
education and the arts.
You can transform culture.
I fund an opera company, symphony
orchestras, museums, theatres,
I have donated thousands of computers
to schools throughout the country.
The question really is,
how many of the people that you
share your discoveries with,
will be altruistic,
and how many will make fortunes
off of your generosity?
Come on in here.
Check this out.
- This is a SYNAPSE satellite.
- You bet.
I've got 240 of these up there.
12 different orbital
patterns, 20 satellites.
The Mother satellite
of each ring
passes over us every
night at 10 o'clock
to allow for station keeping,
re-programming, etc.
They in turn pass the data along to
the sister satellites in their ring.
- That's the coolest I've ever seen.
- I'm total wrapped up in this.
It's like I've got my own mission
control right here on my PC.
Activation codes, IP
addresses, flight path...
- It's the best train set ever, hum?
- You bet!
We've loaded a back door to
receive SYNAPSE transmissions
and all of our OS software
for the past 6 years.
We've developed compression schemes and
file formats that achieve connectivity,
but..
We have a problem.
You know what that problem is?
Your adaptors can't overcome the bandwidth
limitations of wireless hand-helds.
That's right.
Data takes too long to
download so your image gets...
Image, ah, goes fuzzy.
Fuzzy, yeah. Heh.
Can you get this done in
time to meet your date?
With you, I can.
So I understand your friend Teddy
is kind of attached to his parents.
It's very commendable.
The truth is he's...
Milo, I know, he thinks we've...
cloned too many programs
an forced people to buy our inferior
versions and blah, blah, blah..
Ad infinitum, ad nauseum
I've heard it all before.
I even understand it,
it's the nature of
competitive business.
When you're on top,
people attack the quality
of your product.
It comes with the territory.
It's when the attacks get personal the
"Gary Winston is Satan" web sites,
digitizing my wife's face
on porn star bodies...
I don't like that.
You're one of maybe 20
programmers in the world
with the mastery it's going
to take to finish this thing.
We'd love for you to join us.
The future holds limitless
possibilities, Milo.
You decide what the
future holds for you.
Let me know.
You know I look at you and see
something I haven't seen in 20 years.
What?
I see me.
Alice.
Yeah.
So When is Brian
coming for the TV?
I don't know.
I'm going to leave
you two alone, O.K?
Why are you doing this?
Teddy, come on.
He can't hit his date
without you, can he?
Remember that lecture Ginnings
gave? About open source.
Yeah.
He said human knowledge
belongs to the world.
Like Shakespeare or Aspirin.
Teddy, I know you are
disappointed, I just feel like...
this is the right
thing to do for now.
They were interested in you
too. Gary even mentioned you.
Yeah, well.. I'm not
interested in them.
That's fine.
I got what's important to you.
This is important to me.
And I know your are going to
get your venture capital.
We did.
We had to settle for 850
because we lost you.
So, it will be enough.
It'll be enough because
they've got you.
We're both going to
do something great.
Sure.
I just thought we were
going to do it together.
Milo, this is Mr.
Barton from the...
Department of Justice.
- Sorry about the glass.
- No problem.
Don't worry, Milo. I'm
here as a friend.
I understand you signed
up with Gary Winston.
You know Milo, we're at a
great disadvantage with NURV.
I mean our experts are
not as smart as theirs.
The truth is we could do with
a real smart guy on our team
to help us pick our fights.
I'm going to take a real
shot in the dark here, OK?
I can offer you $42,000
a year and a Buick,
if you will change
your mind and join us.
I'm hoping you have a feeling that
that is the right thing to do.
Well, I'm sure what you're doing
is important, Mr. Barton,
I just fell like this is... kind
of my time to make my mark.
Well, like I said, it
is a shot in the dark.
No, no, no, please,
please. Keep it.
If you see something up there
that rubs you the wrong way,
do the right thing.
What are they building?
Oh, That's...
Building number 21.
It's way behind schedule.
It's still off limits.
It's a digital broadcast base.
It's taking forever to get the
fibre optics linked in there.
This is the Daycare Centre.
Gary has put a lot
of money in there.
And the people with kids are not
hot shot geeks or anything.
They're just the payroll
clerks or whatever.
- That's cool.
- I know, that's really cool.
The card is encoded.
It tells us who came through
the door, and when.
If you see a tailgater, that's
somebody coming on your swipe,
report him.
If you see someone wandering around without
ID, it is your duty to challenge him.
I don't give a shit if you're
a stock option billionaire.
If you don't challenge,
I'll have your butt.
He seemed a little tense.
Oh, Shrot, yeah, yeah.
He gets his chain pulled a
lot by the geeks around here
'cause he is non-tech. He's
an ex-cop or whatever.
Whoa..
Lisa actually looked at you.
She has a heavy
graphics background.
She's programming scalable user
interfaces for the SYNAPSE modules.
She's a smart girl.
Every geek has a
thing for Lisa, but
she won't let anyone
get near her.
I have a girlfriend.
What?
You got like a "girlfriend"?
Like a 3-dimensional girlfriend?
That's really rare around here.
So, welcome to the egg.
Everybody listen up.
Can I have your
attention, please?
This is Milo. Milo,
this is everybody.
Hello, Milo.
This is Lori, Darren..
You'll get to know
everybody, I'm sure.
And this...
is your world.
- Your are now officially an egg man!
- Woo!
OK, so we've got a...
electronic copy of Gary's book with
complementary player. As well as...
an audio version narrated
by Gary of course.
A hand held digi, cell phone,
and the keys to
your brand new car.
I guess that's it, man.
Your counsellor will be by to fill
you in on the rest of the details.
- You're gonna love it here.
- Thank you. And thanks for...
My pleasure, man. Good luck.
Hey, Milo!
Just a little advice.
Don't get too close to Stinky.
Hysterical, Desi.
What do they do for a village
idiot when you're here?
Dude! What do they do with all the
air fresheners while you're here?
I don't know.
Busy?
No,
I'm actually waiting for my counsellor
to come by and introduce himself.
Oh!
Hello Milo, I'm Gary.
OK.
Come on. Let me introduce you
to the rest of the team.
Hey, Stinky. Oh, hi, Gary.
How's it going?
Hi Gary, how's it going.
Desi and Stinky are
working on compression.
Josh and Vancat are writing
protocol handlers.
This is Milo. Milo is working...
on the all important adapter.
All right, Milo.
When I announced the
launch date for SYNAPSE,
it wasn't arbitrary,
but it wasn't based on our
progress either, as you know.
If we do not have a workable
version of SYNAPSE by then,
it's over folks.
And this is the glib but little
headline you'll be seeing...
throughout the world.
- Not going to happen, is it?
- No.
- Is it?
Not going to happen.
There are no constraints,
no boundaries.
Surprise me.
Challenge me.
Defy me.
Defy yourselves.
You have a choice.
You can be forgotten, or
you can be remembered
as one of the noble
few who made it.
Now's the time to go way
beyond your potential.
Now's the time to dig
down deep folks.
Now's the time to show
why you are the elite.
The chosen few.
The rare lights that
give this company
its uniqueness,
it's luminescence.
- Now's the time to shine!
- Yeah! Woo!
Corporate condo's are almost as
romantic as they sounded, so she...
she brought me here, and...
Well, I think it's...
I th... What do you think?
Did I tell you he has never been
anybody's counsellor before?
I did. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry, the house is great.
- It's great and so are you.
- Yeah?
- Really?
- Really.
Come on, I love you - You do?
Show me the bedroom.
Most of us who write software achieve
our greatest work before age 30.
As I grow older I know
how important it is..
Are you going to keep working?
Hi, Gary.
In the middle of something?
- No.
- Check this out.
Huh?
Wow!
Who did this? Josh
or Vancat or what..
Somebody, yeah. Think
you can use it?
- Yeah, the compression is awesome.
- Look at that!
- Structure is perfect.
- Yeah.
Oh, god! Oh!
So much fun! Love doing this!
The governor of Missouri has called upon the
president to declare a state of emergency.
In local news, a
tragic car accident
took the life of Portland area computer
software entrepreneur, William Sudd,
a Computer Science
graduate from the MIT
and a genius in his field.
Sudd was found to have both
Prozac and alcohol in his car...
Milo?
Hi.
- You're pretty famous around here.
- Yeah, but...
getting a bit of a
teacher's pet rep.
I wouldn't worry about it
I mean you have to figure most people
around here were their teachers' pets.
- Were you?
- We moved around a lot.
- I barely knew my teachers.
- Me too, I..
- What were you? An army brat or something?
- Yes, something like that.
What do you have there?
I wanted to show you the interface
systems... for SYNAPSE.
OK, here.
- I'm Lisa by the way.
- Yeah, I know.
Hi, you've reached the
offices of Skullbocks.
Teddy and Larry are
out right now.
Leave a message and we'll call you back
when you're out and leave you one.
Hey Teddy, it's Milo.
Just calling 'cause it's
been a while and...
guess I'm kinda hoping you're
not still pissed at me.
Hi - Hey.
- How's it going?
- OK, I guess.
- And Larry?
- Good, yeah.
So, you guys making progress?
Sorry, that's
classified information,
we had to sign all those non-
disclosure forms. You know how it is.
Oh yeah, yeah, me too, me too.
Still, work is not the only
thing to talk about is it?
Oh, of course not.
So, what have you been up too?
Working.
It's good to hear from you,
even though you are
the enemy now.
Gary Winston's office, can
you hold please? Thank you.
Thank you so much for holding,
How can I help you? Let me
just check that for you.
The Department of Justice says that if we acquire
Netmail they will view it as anti-competitive.
Why didn't you tell me this
before we decided to forego RandD?
Well, at the time, they indicated
that it wouldn't be a problem.
They have a bureaucratic
mindset Gary, they...
They do?
I count on you to solve
problems, whatever it takes.
Show me some kind of creativity!
Gary, we're talking
about the law.
It's not like making software.
There are limits.
No limits!
Stop thinking like a
lawyer for a second
and show me some
kind of creativity!
Yes, sir.
He'll have to get back to you
Gary Winston's office,
can you hold please?
You can go on in now, Milo.
Gary Winston's office.
Yes, he is in a conference right
now. Can I take a message?
Gary.
You wanted to see me?
Yeah.
Take a look.
This is amazing. Who's
doing all this?
What does that mean?
- What does that mean, huh?
- Nothing, I, I...
I'm sorry.
That wasn't meant for you.
The Justice Department
is driving me nuts.
They make everything
strategic I do, look sordid.
Every good chess player knows his
opponent's moves before he makes them.
Everyone in business
tries to get ahead.
I get there first,
I'm a bad guy.
What are we doing here?
Are we making chemical weapons?
Kiddy porn?
Are we strip mining? No!
Why are they after me?
The software business is binary.
You're a one or a
zero. Alive or dead.
- It scales, don't you think?
- Definitely, yes.
Here.
It's your copy.
I don't want to speak too soon,
but I think I cracked it, Larry.
I really think I cracked it.
Are you going to tell me
what's bothering you are not?
OK - OK.
Gary gave me a new
compression scheme today.
I said...
"Who's doing all this",
cause I was impressed.
I wanted to know where it
was coming from. Right?
He just lost it, like...
he shouted at me,
he had this look in
his eyes, like I..
- How horrible!
- Yeah.
- Well, where did it come from?
- I don't know.
That's what I've
been asking myself.
I asked around. Nobody
knows anything about it.
You know? So does he have some
genius stowed away somewhere?
And if does, the why not
let him write SYNAPSE?
- I not saying if makes any sense...
- Hey! Honey.
Sesame Seeds. Jesus.
Excuse me... Could you
take that away? Thank you.
- I'm so stupid.
- Hey!
Hey.
He is a genius. Don't forget.
If anybody other than you could write
this thing as quickly as you're saying...
wouldn't it maybe be him?
Yes, yes, you are right,
The guy's a genius. SYNAPSE
is all he cares about,
and I'm being over-sensitive
for a change.
To geniuses.
You know what?
Sometimes it helps to get out of
here. Just for an hour or so.
Hey, Milo!
Brian!
Just dropped off my resume.
Nearly got in the door.
You're living up here now?
I'm systems administrator at the
local public access station,
where any whack job with 100
bucks gets his own show.
God, does it suck!
Can you help me?
- Put it a word.
- I'll see what I can do. Yeah.
- Well, I'm parked illegally.
- OK.
They pushed up the schedule on
all the SYNAPSE applications.
How fast are you going?
There is no second place.
Plus every time I get jammed up,
- Gary comes up with something.
- Did...
- Gary give you a new design or something?
- Yeah
I must have offended
him, 'cause he...
He yelled at me.
People don't ever
just, hand you stuff.
Maybe once. I
reconfigured it anyway.
You're compulsive.
Moments,
precious moments that
you want to hold
that you want to share,
at home, at school, at work.
You'll keep in touch with the
ones you love through SYNAPSE.
The first satellite-delivered,
global communication system.
Share live voices, music,
pictures or video,
data or text,
with anyone, anywhere,
instantly...
Look, Daddy.
SYNAPSE links every communication
devices on the planet.
Because every moment matters.
- I think I have a problem.
- I think you do.
Hi, honey.
Hi.
I didn't expect.. ah..
Lisa this is my...
this is Alice..
Lisa is doing the user
interfaces for SYNAPSE.
Hi.
Milo tells me you're a
really great artist.
Oh? Well he exaggerates.
Well... I've got a lot to do...
It was nice to meet you.
How are you? I'm so surprised.
- Are you OK? Is everything alright?
- Yeah, yeah.
I've always wanted
to come out, and...
you know... see what
this place is like.
- It's really good to see you.
- Yeah.
What did the girl say?
That he's maybe a little less
stressed after you snapped at him.
- It hasn't affected his work though.
- Nothing does.
It's pretty amazing.
What's wrong?
Teddy's been killed.
They've done this
before. Just...
never killed anybody till now.
It's their writing on the wall.
Their hate literature was
scattered everywhere.
Their whole MO. It's like...
they were asking to be caught.
And they've been arrested
twice for beating up Asians.
How come they weren't in jail?
People told us to be careful
in this neighbourhood.
I guess he didn't take
them too seriously.
Yeah. Well. That's our problem.
We don't take anything
seriously. Do we?
It's not on the hard drive.
Hey, I didn't know you guys
were working with fibre optics.
What a bunch of crazy assholes.
And he was on the verge of
something. He was right there.
He was going to show
us the next day.
He told me I should get the VC to line up
appointments with a bunch of companies.
You know?
He said, the answer
is not in the box.
It's in the band.
You know I called him
last week to... 'cause...
I know. He was happy you did.
Be strong, Larry.
Milo.
- May I join you?
- Yeah.
Heard about what happened.
- I'm very sorry.
- Thanks.
Had you talked to
him... much, lately?
Just once.
Things weren't that great between
us and we couldn't talk about work
'cause it was off limits.
Did you have something
you wanted to show me?
- We can save it for another day.
- No, it's okay. I..
It will help take
my mind off things.
- Really?
- Yeah. Yeah.
Okay.
I haven't been able
to sleep all week.
I'm thinking about the push
mechanism in the handler.
And then it just came to me.
It's in the wrong place.
- The wrong place?
- Yeah.
The answer is not in the box.
It's in the band.
"It's in the band."
The answer is not in the
box. It's in the band.
He was on the verge
of something.
Well, where did it come from?
They're being investigated
by the Justice Department...
They just want to
own everything.
We are very close.
Hey, you sure you are all right?
I think I ate
something, I gotta go.
Alice!
Shhh..
Teddy was onto something very
specific, now he's dead.
There's got to be a connection,
Alice, I can feel it.
So what are you saying?
You think they had something
to do with Teddy's death?
I don't know what I am saying.
All I know is all these
ideas keep flying in.
He says any kid working in his
garage can put him out of business.
It's almost like they know
what ever kid is doing.
They're hacking into
people's computers?
I guess they could get into something
with machines. But not Teddy's.
He always had the most paranoid
firewalls to protect his data.
They'd have to have been like...
watching him physically.
Oh. Shit!
I think it's part of a camera.
Number 21 isn't just
a broadcast studio.
It's a surveillance post or something. That's
why they have those dishes on the roof.
Milo, think about
that you're saying.
You honestly think that
he would murder somebody?
I don't know, I
gotta get in there.
There's over 20 buildings over there,
and they're all filled with computers.
No, no, no. This is the only
one with dishes on the roof.
The studio's a front. That's why
they keep postponing the opening.
Ok, now you're scaring me.
Do you wanna just go?
'Cause we can go, you
wanna just... leave?
Go where Alice? You can't get
away from people like this.
People like this. This is
Gary you are talking about.
You don't think I know that?
They're under investigation
by the Justice Department.
I mean, you said yourself that there
are guys showing up all the time.
How could they possibly hope
on hiding a surveillance post?
How could they hope
on hiding anything?
You can't get in there anyway.
They have swipe cards.
They have cameras, It's like
Fort Knox for Christ's sake.
I'm implicated, I'm
implicated Alice.
- No, you're not.
- Yes I am.
Who's been using this code, huh?
Teddy's code. Whoever's
code this is. I have.
How do you think that makes me
feel? This is my best friend,
You need to calm down, now.
- I can't just walk away from this.
- Yeah, but you just can't walk in either.
- You're right.
- Yeah.
You're right.
The construction is
finished by 6 or 7,
the parking lot is cleared
by 2 or 3 in the morning.
- Even the earliest geeks don't get in till about 5.
- Honey, what are you talking about?
What, what are you
saying right now?
I'm thinking about how
I'm gonna get in there,
and find out what the
hell is going on.
OK, then. Was it true
or wasn't it true?
Did you ever really notice? 'Cause
you're sounding like a madman.
I won't pretend like
every-thing's okay, Alice.
It's how I got into this mess.
I..., that's how...
Alice listen, listen,
- I'm not mad at you, Listen to me.
- Don't.
I think I can figure out
a way to get in there.
But I can't do it on my own.
So I need you to help me.
What do I do?
So you believe me?
Just tell me what to do.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. Sir, you've
got to use your own. Where's your ID?
I caught him tailgating.
Building 20.
These cards are your
own responsibility.
- There was an explosion in a closet in building 12.
- What?
Hey, you can't wander around without
ID. Just park your ass in that chair.
Well, what can I tell ya? It's
a pretty basic operation.
You got your time clock. Fuse goes in here.
You just hook it in the switch over here...
So, what do we have here Bob?
A glorified cherry bomb.
Some geek's idea of fun.
I've been saying we need
a camera in this hall.
To protect what? The mops?
Somebody's pulling
your chain again, Bob.
Unless it's a diversion. Milo
Hoffmann is in my office.
- He was tailgating, and I...
- Bob. Milo's not just another geek.
He is very important to Gary. So
let's not go there, all right?
Okay. We'll see you later.
Is everything okay, Bob?
Hey - Hi, Gary.
- Working kinda late. Huh?
- Yeah, uh...
- Can I take a look?
- Yeah.
- That's nice. That's excellent.
- Thanks.
You seem kinda jumpy, Milo.
No. I'm just a...
I'm a little surprised to
see you. Out here, now.
Well, I like to sneak in
late at night sometimes
to see who the
obsessive ones are.
Don't work too late.
I got my eye on you.
- How's it going?
- Big night.
Switched from tea to coffee.
Brought new meaning to my work.
Well. Now he knows.
Nothing in there.
- Maybe he'll get back to work now.
- Yeah. Copy that.
- Speaking of which...
- Okay. I'm on my way back.
- Did you download Callier in San Jose.
- Oh shit.
I'll do it.
- Shame we can't walk in the front door.
- Yeah, wouldn't Bob love that?
Ooh!
Jesus!
I need a thorough
background check.
I want to know
every organization
he's been involved with.
All church groups, all...
- Mr. Barton?
- Yes.
Excuse me...
Do you remember me?
Meelo, isn't it?
Milo
I really need to
talk to you sir...
Right. Give me a few
seconds with Lacy here.
You can go in my office.
I won't be a moment.
Send him the facts as soon as possible.
I don't want to surprise him.
Milo.
Thank you for seeing me, sir.
- No problem, have a seat.
- I'm OK.
- You look a little upset.
- I am sir, I am.
What's the problem, son?
Ah.. well...
My friend, my best friend Teddy,
he was killed in
Silicon Valley and I..
I thought maybe there is some way I
could help them find the suspects.
- You mean Teddy Chan?
- Yes, sir.
Well, I guess you didn't see the
11 o'clock news last night.
San Jose police picked up the suspects
and they're holding them without bail.
That's great. That's...
I hope I'll sleep
better, tonight.
I'm... a little disappointed.
I thought that you decided
to join our side.
No sir, no. I'm... I'm
real happy there at NURV.
But...
Thank you. Thank
you for your time.
- So he didn't mention he was going to the Justice Department?
- No.
You're not losing your hold
on him, are you, Rebecca?
Don't forget your part of the deal.
You've got a very good thing going here.
Phil, he'll tell me
when he gets back.
Well, that will be
the test. Won't it?
Yeah.
Prick!
It's 10 o'clock, I've been
so worried about you.
What did you see in there?
- Nothing.
- Nothing?
It's exactly what
they said it is.
An unfinished broadcast studio.
You know, I think I've been
putting my own guilt on Gary.
Guilt?
Yeah. If I'd done the start up,
maybe Teddy would still be alive.
Or maybe you'd be dead too.
Anyway, I figured, instead of indulging
in all these paranoid delusions
and scaring you, I should do
something useful with my grief.
So I went to see that guy Barton
at the DOJ, remember him?
Yeah.
I wanted to see if I could
help him find Teddy's killers
and it turns out that they got
the guys last night, so...
I have been so
worried about you.
You were right to let
him break into 21.
He felt pretty
foolish afterwards.
He said it was all to do with
his own guilt, you know.
Not being there. Not
doing the start up.
I mean, his best friend
was just killed.
You're convinced he is completely
focused on SYNAPSE again.
- He's not acting?
- No.
He's pretty honest
with his feelings.
I don't think he knows
how to act. All right?
Good. That's all for now.
Lisa, I had to tell someone.
They know everything
about everybody.
There're stealing code
from all over the place.
And sometimes, if someone gets
ahead of them, like Teddy...
- And it's all undetectable.
- What?
The crimes are hand-tailored. These
guys are in the information business.
If it's a Chinese guy,
frame the local racist.
Plus, I'm sure Gary has
maximum deniability.
He tells his people,
surprise me, solve the
problem, defy me.
They turn around and tell the
next person the same things.
That sounds crazy. Why would he put
himself on the line like that?
SYNAPSE...
The guy has invested billions
on getting there first.
He'll do anything to get
his date. He has to.
Lisa...
They killed my best friend.
Maybe others.
I'm living with someone that
they paid to sleep with me.
- We have to do something.
- Like what? What could we possibly do?
I don't know yet. But we are
one step ahead of them.
They don't know I've been in
the Daycare Centre. Just 21.
They let me do that. That's
all they know, though.
Lisa...
Lisa!
I'm sorry, Milo.
All right? I'm sorry.
Lisa, I know why you won't
let anybody near you.
I know what he did to you.
If you leave now, you
could be in danger.
They would use my step father?
They could frame him
if they had too, yeah.
What about the FBI?
Too risky.
I went to the DOJ, but they got a guy
on payroll over there. Maybe others.
Who knows who they're paying?
Well, who can we trust?
I mean how do you let go of a secret
without telling the wrong person?
I don't know.
We tell everybody at once!
See, that way there is no
secret left to protect.
If everybody knows,
they can't touch us.
Right?
What about 60 minutes?
CBS news has partnered with
NURV Information Systems
in a cable news network due
to launch Fall of 2001.
AOL-Time Warner has a 40% stake in Gary's
set-up device. That also takes out CNN.
Disney joins NURV in new
venture. ABC is out.
Look, any of these places
could a mole. Or all of them.
Wait - What?
How close are you to
finishing SYNAPSE?
He's got all the satellites up.
There are dishes on top of 21. He's building
this mega network just for SYNAPSE.
We can connect to everybody on
every device simultaneously.
That's what SYNAPSE is.
That's what we'll use.
Got him.
So what's in the Daycare Centre is a ton of
raw material, and it's all over the place.
What I need you to do is design
some kind of a graphic format
so people can following
what there're seeing.
No problem.
Shit - What?
I'd have to get into Gary's house
to get the satellite addresses.
He's running the whole
thing from his work room.
You mean break in?
I don't know, I don't know...
And what if the dishes on
top of 21 aren't hot yet?
The place isn't even finished.
I'll go up.
You're not afraid?
Testing...
UPLINK ACTIVE.
Welcome back to Good
Morning Portland.
This Thursday, 50 of
Portland's elite couples
will attend a gala party at the
home of Gary and Clarissa Winston.
To raise money for the
Portland Art museum.
Julie is at the museum.
Last year party goers pledged over
2 million dollars to this museum.
- Look at this.
- What?
Why doesn't he invite us to his
party? He's never even met you.
Milo, he has thousands
of employees.
I know Alice.
But this is for the art
museum, and you're an artist.
- If anybody should be invited, you should.
- Ah, hum.
This is not live feed.
This is playback from some other
day. It's been messed with.
- Do we call Randy and Phil?
- Not yet.
I'll have to bust my ass 'cause
I'm not a frigging Mensa.
I swear to God it's
that kid Milo.
Let's run a check on card
entries. Go back two weeks.
Skullbocks, Larry speaking.
Hey Larry, it's Milo.
Hey buddy.
- How's it going?
- I'm good.
I'm... back in the garage.
Didn't want to stay
at that other place.
What's up?
Milo?
You there?
Larry, you got a second?
I might need your
help with something.
You bet man, name it.
Milo.
Giving a benefit for the art museum Thursday
night. Thought you'd like to bring Alice.
That's great. Thank you.
Sorry about the late notice.
You went into 21 twice
without coming out.
You came out twice
without going back in.
Who are you? Harry Houdini?
No, No, No. This things
is screwed up. Look.
It's also got me going
into Daycare that night.
Daycare Centre is
not in your tour.
Exactly, I've never
been in there.
- Milo, we're late.
- I'm coming. I just gotta get...
find some scissors for this...
He called the house. Asked
if we have enough space.
- Alice I'm Gary.
- Hi.
This is my wife Clarissa.
So, this is Alice. Hello.
- Gary tells me you are an artist.
- Yes, I am.
Milo, this is Barry Linder. He's
visiting us from Hollywood.
Barry's studio is going
to help us fill the...
SYNAPSE pipeline. Oh, great.
The marketing
implications are epic.
A kid is watching a movie,
points and clicks at
the laser blaster
and before the reel is even
over, he's bought the toy.
So it's just to hell with story,
and how many toys can you sell?
He, he.
- What about the artist?
- Artist?
The only art left in
America is business,
and you're standing
in Da Vinci's house.
Excuse me, where
is the bathroom?
- It's just around the corner.
- Thank you.
You left the party to work?
I got inspired.
I didn't want to forget it, so
I came here to write it down.
I'm sorry if I was rude.
I know what you're doing, Milo.
I just want to know that it
isn't affecting your work.
I don't know what you mean.
Milo, I'm not blind.
Lisa is very attractive
young woman.
God knows.
Your private life is your own.
But we are very close
to our launch date.
And I need you to keep
your eye on the ball.
- I understand, Gary.
- Good.
Let's go have a drink.
Get the back slash,
get the colon.
Keys kids don't
use but geeks do.
What would Milo want
in here anyway?
They know. Just don't
trust me with it.
So we will get the
evidence first,
ask questions later.
You can get started on that one.
What if he knows
what we are doing.
Do you think he's
toying with us?
How much time do you
need? Two days.
Now did you write the code
to sequence the video files?
Yes, and the audio is done.
The text file will feed
your voice synthesizer.
Hey, you're back.
I bought a hu-nin cookbook.
'Cause we're always afraid for you
to eat in Chinese restaurants.
I've been mincing and
chopping things into
teeny weeny pieces
all afternoon.
- But you never cook.
- I know.
I'm gonna go change.
Uh, uh...
No escaping.
- You look beautiful.
- Thank you.
Milo?
I'm going to go upstairs
and get changed.
I love the way you look.
Thanks.
Hey, do we have any chopsticks?
Yeah.
Great.
Wait...
Right. A toast.
To a long life.
- Is it good?
- It's delicious.
Yeah.
There's something I
need to tell you.
What?
I love you.
- Rebecca?
- Yeah?
Come on... come on. Come on.
See?
Who needs computers?
Gary, believe me, I'm looking
at his prints right now.
You want Phil to handle it.
Whatever you say.
Bastards!
Oh no.
You don't get by me twice, kid.
- You gonna call Gary?
- Screw Gary.
Bob, these guys are criminals.
Now, I am gonna go out
on a limb here because
there's a good chance you're not going to
believe a word of what I'm about to tell you.
You'd be surprised about what
I believe about these people.
Show me what you've got there.
- Milo?
- Get your laptop. We're going tonight.
You said two days!
So, I'm a genius.
- We're not ready. You said two days.
- Yes we are.
Lisa, you gotta trust me, Okay?
I need you to trust me.
Okay.
All right.
He left campus. He's taken some
surveillance data with him.
Don't worry,
we know where he is.
Is Brian here? Brian Bissel.
Who wants to see him?
What's going on here? You
sounded insane on the phone.
We need to do a live
broadcast, right now.
You can't pre-empt yoga
that's our biggest show.
Brian, you want to be a
big deal in life, right?
That's your dream, isn't it?
Will it mean I get
to work for NURV?
After this, there
won't be a NURV.
We're going to bring him down
and you're going to help us.
- That the most insane thing...
- Come on, man...
What have they
ever done for you?
- Okay.
- Great.
Do you want to be a
part of history?
Not really.
All right. How about...
$132?
Fold your hands
behind your back.
Lift the sternum bone, lift
the arms, through the hip...
slowly.
- You're interfaced with the dish.
- OK.
Read me these IP addresses
starting with number one.. Wait.
Phil, come over here.
It's almost 10 o'clock. We're going
to shut down the mother satellites.
- What?
- Read me the IP addresses, starting with 1.
- Gary...
- Just do it, Phil!
It's gone way too far already.
- Go!
10 - 10
192 - 192
Come on, come on..
- It's your software?
- Is it your dish?
All right. Number 2. Go.
Give me number 2.
Milo, some weird-looking
guys just pulled in.
Brian, don't worry about
it. Just give me number 2.
Come on, come on..
Damn it!
Okay, Get out of the there!
- Checked your connection?
- Yes.
- He knows!
- What?
He's shutting down the
satellites one step ahead.
Go to the end.
Give me number 12.
42 - Wait.
He knows I am
shutting them down.
- What?
- I know how his mind works.
Give me the last one, Number 12.
- Gary?
- Just do it!
Ah, give me number 5.
48, 29
Hurry up, hurry up - 230.
Open the door Milo!
One more second.
Guys, we're okay. I've
got it under control.
Give us the disk Milo, come on!
The disk, Milo, now.
Come on, it's over.
Reaching a calm,
peaceful place...
Hey, hey, asshole!
What's with the Mission
Impossible 3, bullshit, Milo?
You're a geek!
Excellent!
They'll be back here in five
minutes with Milo and the disk.
Good.
What do you want to do with him?
Surprise me.
OK, Mr. Shrot, I need the
disk that Milo gave you.
You got something non-geeky
that I could do?
- Yeah, we're gonna need a TV set in here.
- You got it.
So what are you typing
in there, Larry?
IP addresses, it's like calling
up a satellite on the phone.
The first two haven't picked
up. Come on pick up man.
Thank you.
And thank you.
You have achieved a
miraculous thing.
I'm so proud of you.
Forgive me my methods but,
when you got off course, we had to
motivate you to keep working on SYNAPSE.
Without Lisa here urging you on,
we might not have made it.
It's true, Milo.
What we have done
is so important.
Oh my god. What?
Oh my god.
Gary!
Who's got SYNAPSE, Milo?
Does this mean we did it?
Yeah, man!
- That's what I'm talking about.
- Fantastic!!
Yeah, your Jim Broker
never saw us coming,
were coming!
Consumers don't care where
new ideas come from,
just so long as they're
offered a competitive price.
The Software business is binary.
You're a one or a
zero. Alive or dead.
We do have a monopoly here,
we do have a monopoly here,
Those who don't innovate are
doomed to die... doomed to die.
There is no second place.
SYNAPSE will fully unite
the global village.
New ideas are ready to
be devoured, re-defined.
This business is binary,
either a one or a zero...
Alive or dead...
We're surrounded by predators.
Those who don't innovate
are doomed to die. There
is no second place.
Consumers don't care where
new ideas come from.
Just so long as they are
offered a competitive price.
Any kid, anywhere in the world
with a good idea, can
put us out of business.
Alive or dead.
We do have a monopoly
here at NURV.
There is no second place,
one or zero, alive or dead.
Are you insane? What do
you think you're doing?
I'm letting people know
what you've been doing.
Phil, where is this
signal coming from?
I'm working on it, I
am working on it.
Work faster!
A good chess player always knows his opponent's
moves before he makes them. Isn't that right Gary?
You think you know all my moves?
You arrogant little bastard!
You think they're going to come
after me? Now that SYNAPSE is here?
This is the technology that'll fuel
business for the next 30 years!
You think they are going to allow foreign
competitors an opening like that?
Undermine the entire economy?
Over what? A cyber prank?
Then you don't have anything
to worry about. Do you?
The Lawyers are at the gate Gary.
They say the Feds are on their way.
Oh, Jesus!
It's coming from NURV.
It's building 21.
Call security, get
someone over there now.
Break down the door,
if you have to.
But get me that
disk. Get it here!
- How did this happen Phil?
- I don't know.
She called,
She said Milo had SYNAPSE,
he'd left the campus and..
You lied? For him?
You're playing with fire.
If you think for a second I won't
send you back where you came from...
Hey, Gary, I want
you to see this.
Are you still proud of me?
You guys know where you
need to be.. Go, go, go!
Randy, Danny come on, let's get out
of here. Come on. Lets go, let's go.
Rebecca! Rebecca,
come on, let's go.
I'm not going with you.
I'd rather stay here and face the
consequences of my own actions,
than be associated with yours.
This was mine, Milo.
You tell that to the people you
stole it from. Tell it to Teddy!
Come on. It's only a matter of time
before someone owns the information.
You can't stop it. You
just slowed it down.
I slowed you down Gary.
That's what matters to me.
This isn't a game.
In the real world, when you kill
people, they die. For real!
And in the real
world, you're Fucked!
Are you coming?
Let them go.
Tomorrow, he's the most
famous geek in the world.
- Gary, we need information.
- I've been betrayed!
Randy and Phil are missing?
Something's going
on! Take this down.
It has come to my attention,
that certain rogue elements of my company
have been involved in illegal activities
in an attempt to discredit me
and risk control of my company.
I'm most shocked and
saddened by this betrayal.
I will do everything in my power
to co-operate with the authorities
and to bring these
criminals to Justice.
News that FBI agents have
arrested NURV CEO Gray Winston,
TV's, cell phones and PC's were
interrupted world-wide last night
by a rogue broadcast initiated
by programmer Milo Hoffmann.
Police have also arrested these other members
of Winston's team at a Portland airfield
as they attempted to
board a private jet.
Justice officials
reacted swiftly...
Man, Clinton's testimony
didn't get this many hits!
This is... this is awesome!
I mean, there's 400
requests a second, Brian!
- We did this!
- I'm surprised this isn't blowing the server!
Wow, Whoa get over her.
Come here, Come here...
Already over 18 million people have
downloaded the source code for SYNAPSE
from the Skullbocks website.
Now Skullbocks is thought to have originated
right here in this Palo Alto garage.
Hi. We've just a couple of
questions for you about SYNAPSE...
Is Milo Hoffmann going to testify?
Do you know where he is now?
How many hits have
you guys registered?
- Good luck.
- Okay.
Milo?
It wasn't all false.
I know.
Bye.
Do you consider this an ultimate
victory for open source?
- Excuse me.
- Milo?
- We did it, partner.
- Are you going to testify?
Winston always said that
any kid in a garage
could put him out of business.
Is that what you've done Milo?
This is a garage.
Hey, there he is.
We're just now
getting word that...
yes, yes here he is. Here's
Gary Winston himself
being led by US marshals to the
federal court in Portland...
Milo, when did you first realize
that Winston is stealing code?
What is it exactly that you
think you have done, Milo?
And what does it all mean?
It means we've given SYNAPSE back
to the people it was stolen from.
Human knowledge
belongs to the world.
Can we get a picture of
the Skullbocks team?